[music] Something beside me.
A light to the kerosene. [music]
And the places aren't real anymore.
And the faces don't say anything.
In [music] the silent light
of the mind blown sphere.
It's a game. [music]
Devil's chess club.
Devil's chess club. [music]
Welcome to American Exception. I'm Aaron
Good. This is the excerpted first
portion of a full episode of the
American Exception podcast. If you would
like to view or listen to the rest of
the episode, subscribe to the American
Exception podcast on Patreon. We have
hundreds of episodes available for
subscribers. If you want to better
understand the deep politics and history
of the US Empire, American Exception is
the best place to go. The URL is
patreon.com/ameanexception.
Subscribe if you can and either way,
please kindly like this video and
subscribe to this American Exception
channel.
All right, I am happy to be here today
with two former CIA officers, John
Keryaku. How are you doing?
>> Hey, doing well, thanks. Good to see
you, Aaron.
>> Yeah, great to have you here. And Barry
Ecler, it's great to have you back as
well.
>> Always good to spend some time with you
guys. Uh I'm excited that we're going to
be able to talk about some of the crazy
things going on in the world and sort of
historical political significant uh very
significant things today or yesterday.
Uh there's this is really a series of
articles over at dropsite about Jeffrey
Epstein and new revelations. Uh some of
them show uh that Epstein was uh that an
Israeli spy stayed for weeks at a time
with Epstein in Manhattan. that is
significant and more of a direct tie to
uh between Epstein and Israeli, you
know, intelligence. And we also have uh
more emails released about Trump and
Epstein and that he was, you know, more
aware of the let's say controversy and
criminality surrounding Epstein than has
been admitted up to now. And we also
have the swearing in of a Congress
person whose name I I can't recall right
now. Uh but she was
>> Yeah. Yes. Yes. There you go. Um and she
had been kept out by the speaker of the
house from being sworn in because she
was to be the deciding vote about about
Epstein. Uh and so you know to take I
guess she would have forced a vote. Her
vote would have forced a vote on Epstein
disclosure. So that seems to be
happening. Now, this gets into the realm
of intelligence and we were talking
about this a little bit beforehand, but
uh what is
blackmail and in the intelligence
agencies? I've read Secret Agenda. You
know, people know about Jay Garoover. If
you've read Secret Agenda, you know
about uh James Angleton and the Office
of Security, Paul Gainor, blackmailing
people all the time. Uh sexual
blackmail. we know about George Hunter
White and MK Ultra, you know, LSD and
weird sexual black male, you know,
implicated experiments and operations
out there to unwitting people using
prostitutes and all sorts of craziness.
What was your experience at the at the
agency when it comes to blackmail? How
do you think it's a common practice? Do
you think it's sort of an inner sanctum
kind of practice like it was with
Angleton where probably most of the
agency doesn't know about it but it
still goes on or do we outsource it?
What's what's the deal with Epstein and
what what's the significance of these
latest revelations?
>> You want to I I know less about this I
know less about this than John because I
was only at the agency for three years
and almost all of it was only training.
But we were talking about this just a
little while ago and John and I both had
the same experience as career trainees,
which is that we were told explicitly in
these training sessions that the CIA
does not use blackmail. They did once
upon a time, but no longer because they
found that it was just an unreliable and
too high-risk tool for managing assets.
So, is that true is a secondary
question. But I can tell you, I mean,
you don't have to believe me on this,
but why would I make it up? This is what
I was told. I had no ex I had no direct
experience that would either corroborate
or contradict uh what they were telling
me at the time. What I would say is
this. We we're also talking about this
that you know it's more of a guideline
than a rule because it probably is true.
John, again, you you'd know more about
this than I would, but if what you're
looking for is long-term cooperation,
you don't know what it's going to
consist of exactly. you're looking for
intelligence about from a government
asset who's got insight into the
behavior, the policies, etc., the inner
workings of that foreign government,
it's got to be a pretty cooperative
relationship if you're going to get the
good stuff. But if all you need, and
this gets into Jed Garoover, Quintel
Pro, and all that stuff, but if all you
need is someone to not do something, you
just want them to behave in a certain
way, like don't ever go to the press
with X. If you've got incriminating
information about that person, present
the incriminating person and they won't
do X and you're done. It's not some
complicated long-term uh operation that
you need a lot of things. You just need
them to not do X. Blackmail would be
perfect for that. So, it probably
depends on the tool, depends on the
organization, the objectives, that sort
of thing. What do you think, John?
>> I think you're exactly right, Barry. In
in my training, uh I was told the same
thing. When you're trying to recruit an
asset, you want that recruitment to be
over the long term. And in order to have
a successful long-term recruitment, you
need to be able to trust each other.
Even if you don't like each other, you
have to at least be able to trust each
other. And my instructors were very
clear in saying that
we cannot
get
long-term working relationships going on
the right track if we start with
blackmail. It's just not something that
we would do. Now, certainly they did it
in the past prechurch committee.
>> Um,
in the event that,
as you said, you just need for a target
to not do something. Yeah, sure.
Blackmail threats. Um, maybe even you
outsource it to another intelligence
service, another friendly intelligence
service, uh, who might not be as
friendly as you are. Sure. But as a
matter of of day-to-day,
you know, policy, we were told that
blackmail wasn't wasn't going to be
done,
>> which totally makes sense for the stated
reasons that they and say we don't do it
because of X. It makes sense. It's just
that X isn't the whole story. And then
in terms of outsourcing, this is a thing
I think a lot of people miss when
they're analyzing both organizations and
also entire governments. They don't
realize that it's not a monolith. So it
it's easy but a little bit lazy to just
think about well what does the CIA do?
And this is to your point Aaron where
it's like well the CIA is one thing
James Jesus Angleton in in his
counterintel uh thieftdom that is
another story. The left hand doesn't
always know what the right hand is
doing. Sometimes the right hand doesn't
want to know. People talk about um like
the economists don't get me started on
the economist. They do this all the time
when they're talking about Russia and
the Russian. There's never a Russian
government. There's never a Russia. It's
Putin. They make it this singular
person. If you can just understand what
the one person wants or is going to do
or anything like that, then you've
solved the whole problem. But any
society is going to have a lot of
different factions all jockeying for
position and power. And if you don't
have a if you don't have an appreciation
of that, I don't think you have a good
appreciation of reality. So for the CIA
to tell its career trainees like John
and me, hey, this is our official
policy. I'm sure it's true. I'm sure
that is their why would they lie to us?
That is their official policy. What
happens when the left hand doesn't know
what the right hand is doing or when
someone is going off on his or her own
recgnissance? That's just a completely
different story and you have to be aware
of that too. Otherwise, you won't
understand what's really going on
>> 100%.
I would I would uh I think that the
evolution of the way that these things
has been handled is important and it's
of course going to be very hard to ever
really discern completely because we
don't there's just key parts of our
history we don't know but when Angleton
back under JFK when they were doing
operation mongoose and so on and they
were all these assassination plots that
the president and the director of the
CIA were not aware of The liaison
between them was between the island and
the operatives there and Angleton and
Harvey was an Israeli officer, an
intelligence officer. And that did not
come out until 2024
or 25. I wrote about it. And I mean to
me it was very significant. And then
they deleted a page from that testimony
even that you can find it that I found
elsewhere, but you can't find it in
these new releases under Trump that
says, "Yeah, I didn't even really tell
the CIA director Mccon because why would
I want to bother him with a thing like
that?" So you think about what he was
doing there and then you and with no
oversight from anyone. I mean, I guess
Helms knew about it
>> and because he was the director of plans
under Dulles and Dulles had known about
it about arrangements like this with
Angleton in Israel. But this is, I
think, key to understanding some of the
opacity about the the JFK assassination
and the fact that the CIA may not have
>> a a lot of records on the on them to
begin with because it was it was handled
by Angleton and the whole way that he
constructed that apparatus was so there
would be no oversight. The excuse was
that we're penetrated all the time and
were compromised.
>> So,
>> that's a great excuse. It's great.
Really app superficially appealing.
Terrific.
>> He needed that. He needed the Soviets to
be able to pursue the foreign policy
that he wanted. He and the people behind
him, Angleton. Um, but then you fast
forward to the late 80s and you had a a
schism between the right-wing in
America, between pro-Israel people,
neocons, and then Bush and Reagan. And
Reagan recognizes the PLO at the end of
his presidency. And George W. Bush right
at the beginning says, "We got to put
aside this madness." or it's James
Baker, his secretary of state says, "We
got to put aside the idea of a of a
greater pal of a greater Israel, sorry,
once and for all." I mean, he was thrown
down the gauntlet. And look at how many
exposees of deep state things come out
in that little time period. You had this
documentary on the Franklin scandal,
which was sexual blackmail, and it did
trace back to CIA figures. William Kby
was brought in to clean up some of that
mess. You had the you had Israel which
helped to find an Israeli intelligence
agent Arnon Milchon who helped Oliver
Stone public uh get JFK the movie made
which had a big impact on the CIA and
the national security state. Um, you had
that Craig, those Craig Spence articles
on sexual blackmail in Washington that
was by the Washington Times, which is a
far right-wing, you know, paper where
Angleton went on to write, you know,
later in his life before he died. And
they exposed Craig Spence and he seemed
to be CIA connected and involved in
sexual blackmail as well. You had the
BBC Gladadio documentary, which is
amazing that that came out on BBC.
>> Imagine the Gladadio stuff came out when
it was like early 90s, I think.
>> It was under HW Bush. was in that little
time period where there's all these
exposees. You had the people whoever was
feeding Danny Costilo all that material.
>> This was the octopus movie. Yeah. So,
>> so is this is all as a way of
undercutting what Bush Senior, James
Baker were trying to do with regard to
Israeli settlements in the West Bank and
um
>> close. Yeah.
>> Okay. Well, here's what here's my here's
my working theory on all of this based
on Peter D. Scott's writings and
conversations with him and a lot of
other research. The they wanted to
weaken Bush and really put that whole
American establishment on, you know, on
their back foot and afraid of more
exposures and that this was part of it,
including that George W. George Bush,
the CIA and the mob book that was
written and published in 1991 by 1992.
No, it's not. but he also was backed by
a super pro-Zionist guy. So, there's
something about them going after the old
Bush family.
>> But the uh the Brutin book was published
in 1992 and it really was he was a
reporter at a newspaper and it's a
wellressearched book. It's a valuable
book honestly. It's useful but it was
published by a super Zionist publishing
outfit uh that al that had connections
to Richard Pearl I found later and
published all these things by you know
unhinged Zionists. So what I think
happened is part of the reason that Bush
HW Bush loses or a big part of it is
because of Israel and not just not only
does he lose but they wage a kind of war
a clandestine war on the clandestine
state and I think that what happened
>> is that they begin essentially they're
like we're not going to allow the CIA to
do the blackest of black bag jobs
anymore. We're going to keep exposing
them using our media assets and our
people in the government and everything
else and we're going to make them
essentially hand over the most ex you
know dangerous dirtiest jobs to to
Israel. So that's why you get Epstein
who seems to be Israeli handling sexual
blackmail and such and you also have
when they want to assassinate Assange
they go to the SNS casino which is
Israel it's Aden's I mean it's the you
know their joint I guess USIsraeli
citizens but it's literally a Lansky
joint
>> presumably laundering lots of drug money
like it did back when it was in Vegas
now it's in Macau but I think that they
took over the the the clandestine apex
of like dirty tricks and such that seems
to be the explanation that tracks to me
after after the n after the early 90s
after HW Bush
>> you said Assange Aaron you're not
talking about the Mike Pompeo Julian
Assange is that you are okay yeah Mike
>> because I didn't know about any of this
the the Myansky the Sands Casino Shad
Sheldon Adlesen I didn't know about any
of this okay
>> yeah they that was this is a gray zone
article 2020 and it says Israel was uh
or Sheldon Adlesen was the person that
they hired to surveil him illegally this
came out in court proceedings in Spain
in Madrid And not only that, but there
were assassination plots as part of that
operation, too. And it was all handed
out to the Sands Casino Security
Organization. There's another name for
the company, but it's really SN. It's
like a subsidiary of SANS, which is
>> Ad. Yeah.
>> So, this is who handles, you know,
America's the dirty tricks of the the
deep state. You So, when you guys were
told this,
>> that may have been halfway true, that
that it wasn't something the CIA
officers were doing directly. and then
they would just omit the other [__]
>> See, that is so interesting. It's funny.
This is where being a trained lawyer
sometimes helps me because you get at
drafting and negotiating contracts, you
pay really careful attention to the way
language is used and what it's going to
mean. And so I I I didn't think of that
one and I should have. But when people
say, for example, like, well, we don't
do blackmail. We Who's we? Very
important question. You can even get
into definitional things like, well,
what do you what is blackmail? How are
you defining blackmail? But I remember
when Dick Cheney in justifying torture,
sorry, enhanced interrogation
techniques, he said um he said, "We got
actionable intel from uh detainees we
subject terrorists we subjected to
enhanced interrogation techniques." And
immediately that old lawyer part of my
brain fired up and said, "Wait a minute,
what was the what was the chronological
sequence?" Because if they gave you some
actionable actionable intel and then you
tortured them after that, then
technically you did get actionable intel
from people you tortured. It's just that
there was no causal relationship. You
tortured them afterward. They were
already giving you what you needed. I
need a little more precision before I
can uh before I can sign up for even
just what you're describing. So anyway,
I usually notice things like that. But
yeah, good point. We who is we in the
case of the CIA, we only outsource. They
don't, you know, maybe they didn't
torture either. They just send people to
Syria, for example, or Egypt or
wherever.
>> Yeah.
>> Exactly.
>> How much of that was how much of that
was done by actual CIA officers, John,
when you were I mean, you know that more
about that program than I do, and I
don't recall that detail, but was it
usually it wasn't carried out by CIA
officers?
>> Yeah.
>> Or was it?
>> No, it just about none of it was. They
were all They were all CIA contractors.
>> Super interesting.
>> Yeah. And then you get into other
definitional terms too where one thing
they did was just say it's not torture.
Those were all the U memos.
>> Yeah.
>> Uh things that had traditionally been we
were talking earlier about the Azov
battalion which were Nazis until Russia
invaded Ukraine in 2022 and suddenly
Azoff wasn't Nazis anymore and
waterboarding was always torture.
Always. when we were prosecuting other
countries for doing it or describing the
behavior of other countries, it was
always torture until we found it might
be useful for us and then suddenly it
was just an enhanced
>> interrogation technique. So, you know,
the defined terms really matter.
>> Yeah. I mean, this is the the
bastardization or the, you know, of
language in many ways to obscure what's
going on is obviously Orwellian and
really sinister, but that fits with the
themes of the of the days that we're
living through. I got to ask John
because you're a Middle East specialist.
What do you think about Galani now? He's
playing basketball. I think he got good
at playing basketball because he used to
just take severed heads and throw them
into a well or something, right? From
further and further away. They play
horse like that, right? Maybe that's
what's going on. But what do you make of
him posing with with the president in
the White House? It's the craziest [__]
I've ever seen.
>> Yeah.
Honored guest. Uh, listen, I don't mean
to I don't mean to be cynical, but the
only conclusion I can draw [laughter]
is that this guy had to be a long-term
CIA asset. He had to be with his resume.
He should be, you know, buried under the
jail, as as the saying goes.
>> The guy was a member of al-Qaeda. He was
a co-founder of ISIS. He allegedly, you
know, took up arms against the United
States. Everything about this guy shouts
Osama bin Laden light
and then instead
we essentially usher him into Damascus
over the course of a week or two weeks.
The president off the top of his head
just says, "Oh, by the way, I'm lifting
sanctions on Syria effective
immediately." Leading to people
literally dancing in the streets in
Damascus.
Uh Barbara Leaf, an old friend of mine
who's now the assistant secretary of
state for for the near east, jets off to
Damascus with the uh special envoy for
hostage negotiations to make peace and
bring gifts
and then uh
and then he's invited to the White House
for for you know uh to be fetted by all
the Washington swells. The only thing
that I can think of because we don't
change our minds about people quickly
like this. We don't look at US relations
with Cuba. We're still fighting fighting
Fidel Castro and he's been dead for
years now.
>> So why all of a sudden do we just bend
over?
>> We're still pissed about the revolution
in Russia in 1917 and communism.
>> We are. We're still pissed.
>> Why Why he Why do he never forgets?
That's sort of what I think of these
guys. Well, we never forget as long as
it's useful not to forget.
>> If it's useful to forget, then it gets
memory hold or we've always been at war
with East Asia or whatever.
>> And then when the when the Central
Americans say they don't forget about
what the United States did to them, we
just call them communists.
>> Yeah. I mean, you call them communists,
you can kill them. Or you call them
narotists. That seems to be
>> Yeah. Even better now. And then you can
do a kinetic action against them. That's
right. more euphemism.
>> You know, part of what interests me
about uh what's going on with Galani
right now, Twitter's been pretty useful
about it, I think, at least in my feed.
I mean, there is a fair amount of shock
in uh at least among people on Twitter.
How much does that really count uh about
the fact that this former al Qaeda ISIS
guy is now uh uh like a most valued
player welcomed into the White House,
right? The the big lesson for me from
all of this, and I to the extent it's a
useful and accurate lesson, and I think
it is, I wish more people could
appreciate it, the wars don't mean
anything. They don't mean anything. If
you go back to Vietnam, 10 years of
America's war in Vietnam, we killed as
many as 3 million people in Southeast
Asia, 58,000 Americans. Those are just
the numbers of dead. We don't really
count the brain damaged and blinded and
burned and the amputees and the orphans
and all that. We just don't. The
suffering that we meed out on the other
side of the war, other side of the world
in that war is incalculable. And it just
didn't really matter. In 1975, the
country was reunified. The communists
took over and the world kept spinning.
We went into Afghanistan 20 years to
kick out the Taliban. The day we left,
20 years later, the Taliban were right
back in power. And they've been back in
power ever since Al Qaeda. We upended
the entire world and shredded the
Constitution because al Qaeda was an
existential threat. By the way, you
might have noticed all threats are
existential now. They're not threats.
It's just existential threats. It makes
me crazy. I'm like, surely there are
some threats that aren't existential.
Anyway, al-Qaeda is an existential
threat, and we had to shred the
Constitution and and kill millions of
people and displace millions of others
all around the world to fight the
existential threat. Now, excuse me while
I welcome an al Qaeda leader into the
White House because we've installed him
as the president of of Syria. It's
crazy. And I wish people could just see
all this and take a step back and say
maybe all the wars and all the
existential threats and [__] maybe it's
at least a little bit a scam, you know,
racket. Maybe a little bit. It's
severely neurotic people with a lot of
insecurities like Lindsey Graham and
others who are working out their
insecurities by playing the game of
geopolitics. And they should actually be
kept as far away from the game of
geopolitics as possible. They should be
put into therapy where they can work out
their issues safely. Anyway, nobody
really sees that. It's always the ne
Yeah, this time it's true. Uh, but all
the others, sure, it was a scam and a
racket and it didn't matter anyway. But
this time it's true. Makes me crazy that
people can't so many people can't seem
to connect. It's not even connect the
dots, just draw a simple lesson. Like,
not sorry to wrap this up. I didn't mean
to go on so long, but obviously it does
make me crazy. If you have someone in
your life who lies to you repeatedly and
is repeatedly caught lying to you and
now they tell you a thing, isn't there
at least a part of you that's like, they
have a record of bullshitting me. Why am
I assuming this time it's true? But when
it comes to people in their government,
we just instantly forget about the last
round of [__] and believe this this
one can't be [__] It must be true.
>> It's unfortunate.
>> Yeah. I have a line in American
Exception where I I just point out that
it's it's a legal truism that if a
witness is caught lying to you that you
can disregard the rest of their
testimony. But if you would apply that
to the United States who are just lying
constantly day in day out about
especially when it comes to the covert
operations which are all illegal by the
UN charter. I mean most of them are
illegal by the UN charter which is the
supreme law of the land according to the
US constitution because we ratified that
treaty. we just operate in a state in a
in a state of exception. We just do
whatever uh that is expedient for
imperialism. And this is what I I do
think that people realize that a little
bit more is you even see it on the
right, the analysis of Tucker Carlson,
which is strangely critical of empire.
And you know, I don't I'm not going to
try to put a white hat on anybody. I
know he has other views and a history
and different angles that I would, you
know, wonder about. But the truth is
like there are more people on the left
and the right that realize this is a
disaster and the cratering of support
for Israel I think is the most clearcut
uh thing about that and um this is so
this gets into John I I saw it was funny
I saw a Jimmy door segment a video and
they had both of you in it. They had
Barry being interviewed I think by Chank
uh Jen Uger and
>> Oh this is ages ago. Yeah. Yeah. And
then John, they were interviewing you
and they were asking you about whether
you thought we created al Qaeda and you
said that you didn't think that we did,
but do you think that a sort of western
coalition of people could have done
this? Because when you look back at 1991
and that coup in Azerban that that used
al-Qaeda types, although it seemed to be
against HW Bush's general foreign
policy, but it see there were Western
actors involved and that was the
beginning of the post mujaheden 1990s
Mcjihad era we could call it and it took
it was installed in Azerban and the
group that did it was called Mega Oil
which also happens to be the name of
that 1990s super Israel oligarch network
of like uh Wexler and Aden and um the
Crown Lester Crown and all these guys
who were maybe trying to influence
policy in the US, right? They were a
group of super pro-Israel guys. So, I'm
wondering if that's a coincidence or
not. But either way, you had Iran Contra
guys like Richard Cord and Ed Dearborn
setting up this airline like an Air
America in 1991 in Azerban.
And you also had CIA people arranging
the visas for people like the blind
shake and so on, you know, for the
Bosnian jihad at the time and they were
going into the US. So I would I think
that it the origins of al Qaeda are
quite mysterious, but they there's a lot
of reason to believe if the US wasn't
directly involved that the um that
Western intelligence andor people
aligned with Israel may have been.
Looking at Galani now, do you does it
make you reconsider the origins of this
whole
era or or what do you think?
>> Bad bad US foreign policy decisions
indirectly led to the creation of uh of
al-Qaeda. But no, a bunch of a bunch of
white guys sitting in a room saying,
"Hey, let's create a terrorist
organization so we can attack ourselves
and give ourselves a reason to attack
Muslims." No,
>> I I agree. need a reason. We don't need
a provocation. If we want to kill
people, we just go out and kill them. We
don't have to kill ourselves first and
say, "Oh my god, we've been attacked. We
need to go kill Muslims now." I mean,
like I say, I don't want to be cynical,
but no, if we want to kill people, we're
just going to go out and kill them.
>> I agree with all that with a with just a
slight nuance twist, I would say, and
it's this. I notice there are certain
phenomena where
the solution to an alleged problem then
becomes a problem requiring more of the
solution. And what I mean in this
context is during the cold war the
obsession was with destroying the Soviet
Union. And uh and so if that's your
imperative then anything becomes
subordinate anything becomes okay uh as
a tool in service of that imperative
goal. And one of those tools was I a a
critical tool was after 1979 when the
Soviets invaded Afghanistan, the covert
war, the Charlie Wilson's war kind of
stuff. And that meant arming Afghans and
foreigners who came to Afghan to fight
the Soviets, arming them, trading
training them. We called them the
mujaheden at the time, but it doesn't
really matter what we called them. There
there must have been concern, again,
John, you would know more about this
than I would, but there must have been
concern about potential blowback. people
must have said, you know, these people
aren't like exactly our type. They're
not secular. They're not western. And
we're arming and training them. We're
going to have Stinger missiles maybe
floating around there afterwards. It
could become a problem. And I would
imagine that the overall bureaucratic
institutional ethos was we'll worry
about that later. If it's a problem,
we'll worry about it later. Right now,
we got to destroy the Soviet Union. And
part of the reason that they didn't
worry about it enough, I think, is
because then if the blowback happens,
ah, you sort of benefit from that, too.
Now, we got a new war. You know what?
But it's like, hey, you were right, Jim.
Uh, they did turn against us and um,
well, what are we going to do now except
increase military budgets and uh, and go
fight them. Actually, this was that
famous or infamous depending on how you
look at it. James Woolly Woolsey uh,
testimony to Congress where and kudos
for the propaganda because I I I study
marketing and I really appreciate good
marketing, good propaganda just as on a
tactical level. He said, this is right
after the Cold War ends and the Soviet
Union disintegrates. He says, "We have
slain a mighty dragon and now we find
ourselves in a jungle filled with
poisonous snakes." And I just I thought
we cannot recover from that. That was,
you know, well played really. It was
like we don't want the smoking gun to be
a mushroom crowd that's conda rice. And
again, I was like, "Oh god, that's
really good. That's going to be tough to
counter." So anyway, so the
military-industrial complex benefits
either way. It's like we've uh we've
destroyed the Soviet Union. So you may
think that we won't need this gigantic
military anymore. But I actually what
just happened? It got even the world is
even more dangerous than it was when it
was bipolar and so we need to do
something. One last thing about this I'm
sorry because I just saw this in last
week's economist and it was like I meant
to put it on social media and never got
around to it because it's just so the
economist economist thing. the uh the
article was about Ukraine, the war in
Ukraine. And what they said is what we
need is Europe needs to all the European
countries need to increase their defense
budgets, their military spending to I
don't know 5% or whatever it is their
targets. And we're it's an extraordinary
amount of money that's not going to be
spent on bridges, hospitals, education,
ordinary people's benefits, all that
kind of stuff. And then they said, and
even if the war is settled, we're going
to still need to keep spending all this
money because of the threat Russia
poses. And again, I just come back to
just ordinary people. Like, how can you
not recognize a scam when the economist
says we need to increase military
spending because of X, but also we need
to increase it because of the opposite
of X? I'm like, then we just need to
then your goal is increasing military
spending. That's not a means to an end.
It's actually your goal. Just say so.
But then the responsible, well, we can't
say so. Then people would know it's a
scam. We have to pretend. Anyway, so I
think all these these this is how I
would explain like did America did
American leadership or intelligence
agencies or whatever deliberately set
out and say like we're going to create
al Qaeda and they will attack America
and then we'll have an excuse. You know,
you could write a thriller with
something like that. I wouldn't find it
particularly realistic to your point,
John. But the sort of background
incentives and disincentives, how much
of a problem would it be if there's
blowback? Ah, we'll worry about it then
because it's another opportunity for us.
I think that's a human nature kind of
thing we need to take into account.
>> Yeah.
>> I think that's
>> for access to the rest of this episode
and the rest of our vast and growing
library, subscribe to the American
Exception podcast on Patreon. The URL is
patreon.com/ameanexception.
Thanks to Dana Chavaria for producing
this episode and thank you for tuning
in. I also want to express my deep
appreciation to all of our American
Exception subscribers on Patreon. Please
do consider subscribing to the American
Exception podcast on Patreon. The URL is
patreon.com/ameanexanexception.
American Exception exists thanks to our
Patreon subscribers on YouTube. We will
never be viable. You may notice that we
have dropped the Devil's Chess Club
title from these episodes. After David
Talbot had to leave our team due to his
second, more debilitating stroke, I kept
the Devil's Chess Club name and theme
song and intro. I didn't want to close
the book on David's partnership with
Bryce and me. I had hopes that he would
return. David and I had planned to write
two books together after 2024. one on
the ultra Zionist neocon takeover of US
foreign policy and another on the RFK
assassination. It now seems very
unlikely that David will return to
podcasting or to writing. As such, it
didn't make sense to keep using the
Devil's Chess Club brand. Still, to pay
homage to David and the outstanding
books that David wrote with his
wonderful research assistant, Karen
Croft, we're going to keep using the
Devil's Chess Club theme song intro for
our video episodes. David, if you're
listening, know that we miss you very
much. Finally, and again, please do
consider subscribing to the American
Exception podcast on Patreon. The URL is
patreon.com/ameanexception.
Subscribe so that American exception can
continue to mind the darkness.